Finding Aid for Rensis Likert papers, 1929-1983.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Office of War Information
  - Survey of Intelligence materials
    - No. 22, May 6, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - No. 23, May 13, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - No. 24, May 20, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - No. 25, May 27, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 10)
    - No. 25, supplement, July 14, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 11)
    - No. 27, June 10, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - No. 28, June 17, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 12)
    - No. 29, June 24, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - No. 30, July 1, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 13)
    - No. 31, July 8, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - No. 32, July 16, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 14)
    - No. 33, July 23, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Intelligence Reports
    - No. 34, July 29, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - No. 35, August 7, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - No. 37, August 21, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - No. 38, August 28, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - No. 39, September 4, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - No. 41, September 18, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - No. 42, September 25, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - No. 43, October 2, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 18)
    - No. 44, October 2, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - No. 45, October 16, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - No. 46, October 23, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 19)
    - No. 47, October 30, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - No. 48, November 6, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - No. 52, December 4, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 20)
    - 110. 532, December 11, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - No. 54, December 18, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - No. 55, December 25, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - No. 56, January 1, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - No. 57, January 8, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - No. 58, January 15, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - No. 59, January 22, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - No. 60, January 29, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - No. 61, February 5, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - No. 62, February 12, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - No. 63, February 19, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - No. 64, February 26, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 24)
    - No. 65, March 5, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - No. 66, March 12, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 25)
    - No. 67, March 18, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Intelligence Reports (specific topic)
    - White Attitudes Toward Negroes, August 5, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - War Worker Motivations, August 12, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 26)
    - Women and the War, August 19, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Mobilizing Manpower for War, August 26, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - American Estimates of the Enemy, September 2, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Trends in American Public Opinion Since Pearl Harbor, September 11, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Reactions to the Russian Winter Campaign, September 16, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Rumors in Wartime, September 30, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Rubber and Nationwide Gasoline Rationing, October 5, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Realism and the Offensive Spirit, October 21, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Personal Identification with the War, October 28, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Voluntary Participation in the War Effort, November 18, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Campaign to Stall Nationwide Gasoline Rationing, November 24, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - America and the Post-War World, December 16, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 31)
    - Attitudes Toward Peace Planning, March 6, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 31)
  - Intelligence Reports (specific topic, numbered sequence)
    - No. 11. The President's Speech, March 4, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - No. 12. Axis Radio Short-wave in the American Press, March 5, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - No. 13. Cartoons and Newsreels, February 23 to March 4, March 7, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - No. 15. Comic Panels and Strips in Newspapers and Magazines, March 11, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - No. 16. Axis Radio Shortwave in the American Press and Radio, March 4-10, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - No. 17. Mayris Chaney, Congressional Pensions in the Press, March 19, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - No. 21. Farm Problems In Farm Publications and Daily Press, April 1, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - No. 22. The Wallace-Dies Story, Newspaper Coverage and Reaction, April 2, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - No. 43. Newspaper Comment on United Nations, April 29 to May 26, 1942 as recorded in 36 Metropolitan Newspapers, June 4, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - No. 46. Newspaper Comment on Enemy Aliens, April 15 to June 9 June 22, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - No. 64; News Stories and Editorials on Rent Control, Rationing, Shortages, and Price Control in Six Cities, July 20 to August 9 August 18, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 34)
  - Intelligence Reports
    - "What Official Spokesmen Have Been Saying." (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - United Nations Intelligence Digest. (Box 10, Folder 36)
  - Intelligence Reports (topic of newsreels and their promotional and informational content)
    - No. 3. Newsreels and OWI Campaign and Programs, September 1942; December 5, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - No. 4. Newsreels and OWI Campaign and Programs, October, 1942; December 9, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 37)
    - No. 5. Newsreels and OWI Campaign and Programs, November 1942 December 15, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Intelligence Reports (miscellaneous)
    - Negro Attitudes Toward the War, January 22, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - How the Populace Regards the Government's Handling of War News, January 22, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - Public Reactions to the Sale of Defense Bonds and Stamps, March. 6, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 38)
    - People's Attitudes Toward the Government's Information Policy, March 7, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Some Preliminary Indications of U.S. Attitudes Toward our Allies--Britain, Russia and China, March 9, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - The Problem of Enemy Aliens Along the East Coast, June 15, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 39)
    - Gas and Rubber A Summary of Recent Intelligence Material, June 25, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Use of American Newspaper and Periodical Materials in Axis Short-Wave (April 1-May 1, 1942), July 14, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Weekly Report on Authoritative Statements July 13-July 19 inclusive, July 20, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - The Enemy Propaganda Attack on United Nations' Unity in Broadcasts to the United States, July 30, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - Who is the Enemy? Peoples? Or Regimes?, August 11, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - The Nature of the Enemy as Seen by Private Thought Leaders, August 13, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 41)
    - The War Economic Program, August 29, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Official Statements on Manpower, September 22 1942 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Community Tensions in Three Army Camp Impact Areas, December 9, 1942 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Baltimore's efforts to meet some of its War Problems, April 24, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Public Appreciation of the Problem of inflation (Memorandum No. 66), October 27, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 42)
    - Women Report on Canning (Special Memorandum No. 106), February 19, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - What the Civilian Thinks (Memorandum No. 82), July 18, 1944 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Some Recent Trends in French Attitudes Toward the United States (Report No. 133), July 2, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - The English and French Look at Their Allies (Report No. 134), July 6, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Dissatisfaction with German News Sources: A Survey of Civilian Opinion in Darmstadt, (Report No. 136), July 9, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Some Post-Defeat Attitudes of German Prisoners-of-War (Report No. 135), July 10, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - Radio Listening in France: Spring, 1945 (Report No. 138), July 18, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Japanese Personality and Reactions as Seen in Soldiers' Diaries (Report No. 30), December 19, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - The Attitudes of Japanese Prisoners of War An Overall View (Report No. 31), December 29, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Pro-American Sentiment Among the Japanese During the War (Report No. 32), December 31, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 44)
    - Miscellaneous and fragmentary (Box 10, Folder 45)
  - Miscellaneous files
    - Publications, 4 folders (Box 11, Folder 1-4)
    - Newsletter
      - Current Surveys, 1943 (Box 11, Folder 5)
      - Current Surveys, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - Minutes of Bureau of Intelligence staff meetings, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Administrative memoranda (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Planning Committee Papers (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Victory Committee Papers (Box 11, Folder 10)
    - Background files
      - Morale questionnaire (Box 11, Folder 11)
      - Anti-British Feeling in the United States (Box 11, Folder 12)
      - Some problems of the Negro in Mobile (Box 11, Folder 13)
      - West Coast Reactions to the Japanese Situation (Box 11, Folder 14)
      - Negro war morale (Box 11, Folder 15)
      - Miscellaneous (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Administrative files
    - Topical Memoranda, March 4, 1942-November 27, 1942 (Box 11)
      (most authored by Likert; Negro-White relations, meat-rationing, labor conflicts, women's attitudes toward the war, etc.)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 11)
  - Reports and Memoranda
    - 1942
      - Pacific Coast Attitudes Toward the Japanese Problem, 2/28/1942 (Box 11)
      - Intelligence Report No. 51, 11/27/1942 (Box 11)
      - Special Memorandum No. 45: The People Appraise Their War Information, 3/26/1943 (Box 11)
      - Special Memorandum No. 46: Preliminary Report on Absenteeism in War Industries, 3/27/1943 (Box 11)
      - Special Memorandum No. 47: A Pilot Study of American Sentiment Toward the British, 3/29/1943 (Box 11)
      - No. 75: Price Panel Assistants; A Study of Their Recruitment Use in the OPA Price Panel Program, 4/27/1944 (Box 11)
      - No. 131: German Prisoner Reactions to KZ Booklet on Atrocities (KZ Booklet attached), 6/23/1945 (Box 11)
- United States Strategic Bombing Survey, US War Dept., Morale Division
  The U.S. Strategic Bombing Survey series consists of final reports and extensive background information in the form of field notes, completed questionnaires, and transcripts of interviews with detailed information on conditions in Germany and Japan during and immediately after World War II. Some of the work documented in this series was conducted during the occupation of Japan and relates to the aftermath of the dropping of the atom bombs.
  - Departmental Reports
    - The Effects of Strategic Bombing on the German War Economy (Box 11)
    - The Effects of Strategic Bombing on German Morale
      - Published report, 2 volumes (Box 11)
      - Field Notes, 1945. [22-17] (Box 11)
      - Questionnaires and Interview Transcripts., 4 folders (Box 11)
      - Background. [22-22] (Box 11)
    - United States Strategic Bombing Survey Over-all Report (European War), September 1945 (Box 11)
    - Summary Report (Pacific War) (2 versions), July 1946 (Box 11)
    - Japan's Struggle to End the War, July 1946 (Box 11)
    - The Effects of Strategic Bombing on Japanese Morale, June 1947 (Box 12)
      - Published Report (Box 12)
      - Transcripts of Interrogation and Post World War II Military and Civilian Personnel, 1945 (Box 12)
      - Background Files, 1945 (Box 12)
    - The Effect of Bombing on Health and Medical Care in Germany, 1 volumes; 1 folders (Box 12)
    - The Effects of Atomic Bombs on Hiroshima and Nagasaki, June 1946 (Box 12)
    - The Effects of Atomic Bombs on Health and Medical Services in Hiroshima and Nagasaki, March 1947 (Box 12)
  - Miscellaneous Reports and Documents
    - 1941
      - "German Psychological Warfare Survey and Bibliography" (Box 12)
      - Nazi Document, "Die Medaille fur Deutsche Volfsplege" (Box 12)
    - 1942-1943
      - Morale and Propaganda excerpts (Box 12)
    - 1942-1945
      - Military Orders and Papers, 3 folders (Box 12)
    - 1944
      - Notes and Diary notations (about V2 buzz bombs in London) (Box 12)
    - 1945
      - "A Detailed Study of the Effects of Area Bombing on Wuppertal Germany,", November 1945 (Box 12)
      - Appraising and Improving American Occupation of Enemy Countries by means of Scientific Resources, November 1945 (Box 12)
        (Proposal to State Department and General Clay for Sample Survey Unit in Post-war Germany, 1945)
      - Area Studies Division Report, September 1945 (Box 12)
      - Austrian Occupation Studies (Lewis Gleeck), 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Colonel Harold Carson War Document (Box 12)
      - Civilian Defense Division Final Report, October 1945 (Box 12)
      - German Questionnaires, 2 folders (Box 12)
      - Japanese Questionnaire (Box 12)
      - Morale Division Report (Box 12)
      - Oil Division Final Report, August 1945 (Box 12)
      - Ordnance Industry Report, October 1945 (Box 12)
      - "Poll of German Prisoner of War Opinions" Office of the Provost Marshall General (Box 12)
      - "Some Psychological Hypotheses On Nazi Germany" Library of Congress Experimental Division for the Study of War Time Communications (Box 12)
    - 1948
      - A Case Study of a Social Survey, Japanese Survey, United States Bombing Survey (Box 13)
  - Administrative
    - Topical and miscellaneous files, 0.3 linear feet (Box 13)
      (unprocessed)
- Institute for Social Research / Survey Research Center
  The Survey Research Center/Institute for Social Research series contains materials from the early project files of the Survey Research Center. The project files consist of attitude surveys and studies. The files contain both background material and final reports. This series also contains notebooks of project materials, building fund raising files, and correspondence files. Materials in this series are largely arranged chronologically with the exception of project reports which are arranged in their original sequential numbering system.
  - Background
    - Annual report, articles, etc. (Box 13)
  - Project files
    - Sources of Information, 1946 (Box 13)
    - S.7A. Five Americans Discuss Our Relations With the U.S.S.R., January 1947 (Box 13)
    - S.14. Four Families Discuss their Financial Position, June 1948 (Box 13)
    - S.15. Four Americans Talk About Their Cities, October 1947 (Box 13)
    - S.17. Life Insurance Ownership Among U.S. Families, March 1948 (Box 13)
    - S.18. Four Americans Discuss Aid to Europe, December 1947 (Box 13)
    - S.18-I. American Attitudes Toward Aid to Europe, January 1948 (Box 13)
    - S.18-II. Sources of Information About World Affairs, February 1948 (Box 13)
    - S.18-III. Citizen Participation in Problems of World Affairs, February 1948 (Box 13)
    - S.18-IV. Trends in Attitudes Toward Foreign Affairs, March 1948 (Box 13)
    - S.19. Special Tabulations Regarding Magazine Readers, November 1947 (Box 13)
    - S.21. The Detroit Edison Study, A Company-Wide Study of Employee Attitudes, 1949 (Box 13)
    - S.21. The Detroit Edison Study (cont.), 1949 (Box 14)
    - S.27. A Study of Attitudes and Suggestions of Ground School Instructors of the Naval Air Training Command, Pensacola Naval Air Station, March 1948 (Box 14)
    - Automobile Ownership, 1948-1949 (Box 14)
    - S.29. Relation of Six Supervisory Traits to Nine Employee Attitudes, April 1950 (Box 14)
    - S.39. Prudential Experiment, 1948 (Box 14)
    - S.47-I. A Comparison of High Morale and Low Morale Employees in Detroit Edison, June 1949 (Box 14)
    - S.47-II. The Detroit Edison Study, June 1949 (Box 14)
    - S.47-III. The Detroit Edison Study, February 1950 (Box 14)
    - S.52. Three Citizens of Albany, New York Discuss International Affairs, May 1949 (Box 15)
    - S.58. Caterpillar Study, 1950 (Box 15)
    - S.59. 1950 Survey of Consumer Finances, 1950 (Box 15)
    - S.60. Survey of Consumer Finances, 1950 (Box 15)
    - S.61. 6th International Study, Department of State. Attitudes Toward Foreign Affairs, 1950 (Box 15)
    - S.64. Political Science Conference. (Box 15)
    - S.65. Prudential Experiment. (Box 15)
    - S.66. APA and Topology Conference, 1950 (Box 15)
    - S.70. Cooperative Flight Research. (Box 15)
    - S.73. Economic Values of the Public. (Box 15)
    - S.75. Third Annual Summer Institute, 1950 (Box 15)
    - S.95. Maytag Employee Study, 1951 (Box 15)
    - S.95. Maytag Employee Study (cont.), 1951 (Box 16)
    - Miscellaneous printed ISR reports (Box 16)
    - Project reports and questionnaires, 6 volumes (Box 17)
  - Building fund-raising files
    - Campaign managers files, 1961 (Box 18)
  - Correspondence file
    - Ca. (W-Z), 1947-1951 (Box 18)
    - Ca. (A-M), 1952-1953 (Box 18)
    - Ca. (N-Z), 1952-1953 (Box 19)
    - Named files
      - American Statistical Association (Box 19)
      - Bose, S.K. (Box 19)
      - Coffman, Ray (Box 19)
      - Clara Elizabeth Study (Box 19)
      - Likert notes (Box 19)
  - Administrative and Miscellaneous files
    - Topical Files, 0.6 linear feet (Box 19)
    - Topical Files, 0.6 linear feet (Box 20)
- Early Career
  The Early Career series documents Likert's work as a researcher director of research in the 1930s. The first two small series - Psychological Corporation and Newell-Emmett Company - document specific studies, one of which concerns the public's radio listening habits and gasoline purchasing habits. The subseries, Life Insurance Sales Research Bureau, documents Likert's entry into the survey research field. This portion of the collection includes lecture notes and student papers written for Likert while at Columbia University. It also includes early opinion survey questionnaires and correspondence produced while with the Life Insurance Sales Research Bureau.
  - The Psychological Corporation
    - Market Research Statement, February 4, 1935. (Box 21)
    - A Study of the Psychological Factors Influencing the Drinking of Plain Milk by Adults, January 29, 1935 (Box 21)
    - Background Files Cigarette Preference Study, 121-43, ca. 1934. (Box 21)
    - Delaware, Lackawanna and Western Coal Company Study,., ca. 1934-1935 (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous Research, ca., 1934-1935 (Box 21)
    - Methodology Papers (Box 21)
  - Newell-Emmett Company
    - Radio Listening Habits and Gasoline Purchasing Habits of Car Owners Who Read Colliers, Liberty and Saturday Evening Post, May 7, 1935 (Box 21)
    - Background to Radio Listening Habits and Gasoline Purchasing Habits of Car Owners Who Read Colliers, Liberty and Saturday Evening Post, 1935 (Box 21)
    - Miscellaneous Research, 1935 (Box 21)
  - Life Insurance Sales Research Bureau
    - 1929
      - Lecture Notes, "Attitude Problems and Experimental Methods" (Box 21)
    - 1930
      - Survey of Opinions Questionnaire (Box 21)
    - 1931
      - Lecture Notes, "Definition of Attitude" and student papers (Box 21)
    - 1932-1938
      - Attitude Surveys, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - 1933
      - Pacifism Pamphlets (Box 21)
    - 1935
      - "A Study of the Attitude of A Group of Relief Workers Toward Work Relief" (By Sydney Roslow and Rensis Likert) (Box 21)
    - 1935-1939
      - Life Insurance Sales Research Bureau Correspondence, 2 folders (Box 21)
    - 1939
      - "Organizing for Sales" Life Insurance Study of the Marketing Methods of Fire Companies in Other Lines of Business (Box 21)
- Association and Committee Activities, ca., 1938-1949
  The series related to Likert's Association and Committee activities (ca. 1938-1949) is incomplete, and documents only a small percentage of Likert's professional involvements, notably correspondence and bulletins from the American Association for Applied Psychology, 1938-1945; fragmentary background for a proposal of the American Psychological Association, Society for the Psychological Study of Social Issues, 1947; notes for a 1945 discussion before the British Social Psychologists; correspondence, charts, and reports associated with the Committee for National Morale, ca. 1940-1941; summary records of the 1949 meeting held in Paris of the Committee of Scientific Experts on International Research Laboratories; and conference minutes (1944) and miscellaneous papers (ca. 1942-1944) of the Committee on Food Habits.
  - American Association for Applied Psychology, (correspondence, bulletins, etc.),., 1938-1945 (Box 21)
  - American Psychological Association, Society for the Psychological Study of Social Issues
    - Draft Proposal for the Establishment of a United Nations Institute of the Human Sciences, 1947 (Box 21)
    - Background to the Proposal for the Establishment of a United Nations Institute of the Human Sciences, ca., 1947 (Box 21)
  - British Social Psychologists (notes for discussion before), May 11, 1945 (Box 21)
  - Committee for National Morale
    - Correspondence and charts, ca., 1940-1941 (Box 21)
    - Reports, ca., 1940-1941; 5 folders (Box 21)
  - Committee of Scientific Experts on International Research Laboratories
    - Summary Records of Meetings held in Paris, August 16-25, 1949 (Box 21)
  - Committee on Food Habits
    - Conference minutes February 29, 1944 miscellaneous, ca. 1942-1944 (Box 21)
- Rensis Likert and Associates
  The Rensis Likert Associates series is primarily correspondence generated during the 1970s. This series consists of both incoming and outgoing correspondence which illuminate the nature of his consulting. Both individuals and corporations are represented in the correspondence. Correspondence retains the original alphabetical arrangement as received by the library.
  - American Management Association, 1973-1974 (Box 22)
  - Asiatic Society, 1976 (Box 22)
  - William F. Dowling (American Management Association), 1972-1977 (Box 22)
  - David W. Ewing (Harvard Business Review), 1978 (Box 22)
  - Eric Flamholtz, 1973 (Box 22)
  - Harvard Business Review, 1975; 1979 (Box 22)
  - Frank E. Humberger, 1975 (Box 22)
  - Carol Huss, 1974 (Box 22)
  - IBM, 1978 (Box 22)
  - Law Enforcement and Corrections Agencies, 1976 (Box 22)
  - Howard Lockwood (Lockheed Aircraft), 1975-1978 (Box 22)
  - Sven Lundstedt, 1973-1982 (Box 22)
  - Management Today, 1976 (Box 22)
  - James Marshall, 1971-1978; 2 folders (Box 22)
  - David Mullen, 1974 (Box 22)
  - Gardner Murphy, 1975-1980 (Box 22)
  - David Oates (International Management), 1975-1977 (Box 22)
  - Hollis W. Peter, 1971-1972 (Box 22)
  - Lyman Randall, 1974 (Box 22)
  - Donald Stone, 1970-1980 (Box 22)
  - J. Philip Wernette, 1972-1973 (Box 22)
  - Benjamin Woodson, 1975; 1979 (Box 22)
  - Stanley Zwemer, 1978 (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous, 1978-1981 (Box 22)
  - RLA Handbook (Box 22)
- Published Works
  The series, Published Works, consists of articles and reprints of Likert's writings. The series spans 1934 to 1979, covering both his earliest and latest work. The series is arranged chronologically and includes a bibliography of his writings. Six booklets on morale produced for the Life Insurance Sales Research Bureau in 1940 are included here. They were produced by Likert, but contain no statement of authorship.
  - Bibliography (Box 22)
  - 1932
    - "A Technique for the Measurement of Attitudes" (Box 22)
  - 1934
    - "The Effect Upon the Reliability of Attitude Scales of Using Three, Five or Seven Alternatives" (with Sydney Roslow) (Box 22)
  - 1939
    - "Organizing for Efficient Selling" (Box 22)
  - 1940
    - Life Insurance Sales Research Bureau Series
      - "Morale-Building Starts at the Top" (Box 22)
      - "Morale and Agency Management Volume I: Morale-the Mainspring of Management" (Box 22)
      - "Morale...and Agency Management Appendix to Volume I" (Box 22)
      - "Morale and Agency Management Volume II: Morale-What It Is and What It Does" (Box 22)
      - "Morale...and Agency Management Appendix to Volume II" (Box 22)
      - "Morale and Agency Management Volume III: Morale-How To Build It" (Box 22)
      - "Morale and Agency Management Volume IV: Morale and Motivation" (Box 22)
  - 1941
    - "Democracy in Agriculture-Why and How?" (Box 22)